Guide to the David Wojnarowicz Papers MSS.092
Fales Library and Special Collections
David Wojnarowicz Papers
circa 1954-1992
Fales Library and Special Collections
Wojnarowicz, David
MSS.092
211 Linear Feet in 117 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, 103 flat boxes, 49 flat file folders, 44 box binders, 12 card boxes, 59 film cans, 1 rolled storage tube, 3.5 CD boxes, and a folder in an oversized shared flat box
David Wojnarowicz was a painter, writer, photographer, filmmaker, performer, and activist. He made super-8 films, created the photographic series "Arthur Rimbaud in New York", performed in the band Three Teens Kill 4 - No Motive, and exhibited his work in well known East Village galleries. In 1985, he was included in the Whitney Biennial, the so-called "Graffiti Show". He died of AIDS on July 22, 1992. The David Wojnarowicz Papers includes journals, correspondence, manuscripts, photography, film, video and audio works, source and production materials, objects, and ephemera.
Provenance
The David Wojnarowicz Papers were purchased in September 1997 from the estate of David Wojnarowicz with the assistance of Tom Rauffenbart, executor of the estate. The collection was transferred from a storage unit on the West side of Manhattan to the Fales Library at New York University.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biographical Note
David Michael Wojnarowicz was an openly gay artist, writer, and activist who chronicled a late-twentieth century New York ravaged by AIDS. His multi-media work is notable for combining elements of personal narrative with erotic, often confrontational imagery.
Wojnarowicz was born on September 14, 1954 in Red Bank, New Jersey. Following his parents' divorce, Wojnarowicz moved with his mother to New York City, where he claims he began hustling at age eleven. He attended the High School of Music and Art in Manhattan for a time, although he never graduated. Wojnarowicz left his mother's apartment at age sixteen to live on the streets, where for two years he was a victim of numerous assaults, before seeking shelter at a halfway house.
In the ensuing years, Wojnarowicz traveled, often by hopping trains and hitchhiking. He lived in San Francisco, as well as in France with his sister, before eventually returning to New York, where he worked as a busboy or janitor to support himself and his art. His activities at this time included performing in a band (Three Teens Kill 4 - No Motive) featuring children's instruments and tape recordings of found sounds, and documenting the Lower West Side's marginal characters through his film, writing and photography. His well-known series Arthur Rimbaud in New York, featuring images of the artist wearing a photographic mask of the symbolist poet, was created in 1978-79.
In the early 80s Wojnarowicz became known in the East Village art scene for making use of re-contextualized stencils, found maps, and grocery-store price signs to produce stark tableaux. By the mid-80s, after the death of his lover, the photographer Peter Hujar, and his own diagnosis with the disease, AIDS became a constant undercurrent in his work. The artist continued to work with images of decay, disaster and sexuality, adopting a militant stance against what he perceived as the complacency and ignorance surrounding the disease. An iconic image of the Wojnarowicz from this time appears in the film Silence = Death, where he appears with his mouth sewn shut in a reference to ACT-UP slogan.
At this controversial point in his career he was drafted in the "culture wars": the NEA rescinded and finally restored funding for an exhibition catalog in which he attacked various public figures, and he was criticized by both a member of Congress and the American Family Association. His book Close to the Knives: A Memoir of Disintegration was published in 1991. He continued to produce work until his death in 1992 at age 37.
SOURCES:
"David Michael Wojnarowicz."The Scribner Encyclopedia of American Lives, Volume 3: 1991-1993. Charles Scribner's Sons, 2001. Reproduced in Biography Resource Center. Farmington Hills, Mich.: Gale, 2009. http://galenet.galegroup.com/servlet/BioRC
"David Wojnarowicz." Contemporary Artists, 5th ed. St. James Press, 2001. Reproduced in Biography Resource Center. Farmington Hills, Mich.: Gale, 2009. http://galenet.galegroup.com/servlet/BioRC
Kimmelman, Michael. "David Wojnarowicz, 37, Artist in Many Media.(Cultural Desk)(Obituary)." The New York Times (July 24, 1992): NA. New York Times and New York Post (2000-present). Gale. New York Public Library. 22 May 2009. http://find.galegroup.com/itx/start.do?prodId=SPN.SP00.
BIBLIOGRAPHY: Written Works by David Wojnarowicz:
Close to the Knives: A Memoir of Disintegration, New York: Vintage Books, 1991.
David Wojnarowicz: Brush Fires in the Social Landscape, Aperture, 1994.
Memories that Smell like Gasoline, San Francisco, ArtSpace Books, 1992.
Seven Miles a Second, New York: DC Comics, 1996.
Sounds in the Distance, London: Aloes Books, 1982.
Waterfront Journals, New York: Grove Press, 1996.
SOLO EXHIBITIONS:
1982: Milliken Gallery, NYC
1983: Hal Bromm Gallery, NYC; Civilian Warfare, NYC
1984: C.A.U.C. Buenos Aires, Argentina; Civilian Warfare, NYC; Anna Friebe Galerie, Cologne, West Germany; Gracie Mansion Gallery, NYC.
1985: Messages to the Public, Times Square Spectacolor Board, NYC
1986: Gracie Mansion Gallery, NYC; Anna Friebe Galerie, Cologne, West Germany; Cartier Foundation, Paris, France
1987: Ground Zero Gallery, NYC; Gracie Mansion Gallery, NYC
1989: PPOW, NYC
1990: David Wojnarowicz, Tongues of Flame, University Galleries, Illinois State University, Normal, Illinois. PPOW, NYC
1991: Exit Art, NYC, David Wojnarowicz: Tongues of Flame.
SELECTED GROUP EXHIBITIONS:
1980: Lower Manhattan Drawing Show, Mudd Club, NYC; Erotic Show, Club 57, NYC;: Hunger, Leo Castelli's Staircase, action installations with Julie Hair, NYC
1982: Fast, Milliken Gallery, NYC; Hunger Show, Gallery 345, NYC; Beast Show-Cock-a-Bunnies, PS.1, Long Island City, NY, action installation; 3 Person Show, Civilian Warfare Gallery, NYC; Famous Show, Gracie Mansion Gallery, NYC; Street Image Brawl (PADD), Franklin Furnace, NYC
1983: Sex Show, Sharpe Gallery, NYC; Underdog, East 7th Street Gallery, NYC; The Terminal Show, Brooklyn Terminal, NYC; Sofa/ Painting, Gracie Mansion Gallery, NYC; Soup Kitchen Benefit, Fashion Moda, NYC; From the Streets, Greenville County Museum of Art, South Carolina;: Summer Show, Hal Bromm, NYC; Speed Trials, White Columns, NYC; Wardline Pier Project, organized by David Wojnarowicz & Mike Bidlo, NYC; Intoxication, Monique Knowlton Gallery, curated by Nicholas Moufarrege, NYC; 3 Part Variety, Milliken Gallery, NYC (co-curator)
1984: East Village Artists, Virginia Museum of Fine Art, curated by Margo Crutchfield, VA; Gracie Mansion Gallery, NYC (installation).; Neo York, University Art Museum, University of California, curated by Phillis Plous, Santa Barbara, CA.; Acid Show, Sensory Evolution Gallery, NYC; Indigestion, PPOW Gallery, NYC; New Galleries of the Lower East Side, Artists Space, NYC; 25,000 Sculptors from Across the USA, Civilian Warfare, NYC; Portraits, PS.1, curated by Jeffrey Deitch, Long Island City, NY
1985: Whitney Biennial, Whitney Museum of American Art, NYC; Anchorage, installation, Brooklyn, NY; Indigestion, PPOW Gallery, NYC; #2 Smart Art Too, 55 Mercer St. Gallery, NYC; Graffiti and East Village Artists, Librizzi Gallery, NYC; East Village Sampler, Jones Troyer Gallery, NYC; Getting Off, Civilian Warfare, NYC; You Killed Me First Installation#8, collaboration with Richard Kern, Ground Zero, NYC; Benefit for the Kitchen, Brooke Alexander, NYC; 1986 The All-Natural Disaster Show, Bronx Council on the Arts, New York; The East Village, Fashion Institute of Technology, NYC; Heads, Mokotoff Gallery, NYC; Homage to Nicholas Moufarrege, Gabrielle Bryers Gallery, NYC
1987: Art Against Aids, Gracie Mansion Gallery, NYC; Exposed and Enveloped, Laurence Miller Gallery, NYC; Redtape Magazine Benefit, EM Donahue Gallery, NYC; Scott Hanson Gallery, NYC
1988: Vollbild- AIDS, N.G.B.K. Berlin, West Germany; Products and Promotion, Franklin Furnace, NYC; Unknown Secrets: Art and the Rosenberg Era, Traveled to: University of Colorado Art Galleries, University of Colorado, Boulder, Installation Gallery.; Still Trauma, Milford Gallery, New York; Fermate show/ installation/ films/ performance in Cologne Train Station, organized by Rilo Chmielorz.
1989: Witnesses Against Our Vanishing, Artist's Space, NYC, curated by Nan Goldin; Departures Photography 1924-89, Hirschl & Adler Modern, NYC; Art About AIDS, Freedman Gallery, Albright College, Reading, PA
1995-96: Temporarily Possessed The Semi-Permanent Collection, New Museum of Contemporary Art, NYC.
1996-97: Sex/ Industry, Guest curated by John Yau, Stefan Stux Gallery, NYC.
1997-98: Male, curated by Vince Aletti, Wessel + O'Connor Gallery, NYC.
FILMS/ VIDEOS/ AUDIO RECORDINGS:
1979: Heroin (partially destroyed), color, super-8
1983: 3 Teens Kill 4- no motive/ LP, Point Blank Records
1985: Satan Teens (made with Tommy Turner) b&w super-8, 90 minutes. (unfinished)
1987: A Fire in my Belly, filmed in Mexico City and various border towns as well as NYC, b&w and color super-8, 30 minutes.(went through 2 versions then disassembled for other projects.)
1987-88: Untitled (The Death of Peter Hujar), b&w super-8, approx.30 minutes, unedited.
1988: Beautiful People, starring Jesse Hultberg, approx. 30 minutes (soundtrack unfinished)
1989: Teaching a Frog to Dance (or: Building a Patriotic Beast) b&w super-8, 2; minutes, unfinished.; What's This Guy's Job in the World, 2 minutes, color video.; In This House..., 3 minutes, color video.; Howdie Doody Goes for a Drive, b&w super-8, 25 minutes,(unfinished).; Untitled, or Using My Sexual Energy As a Tool to Fight the State Is As Good a Tool As Any Other, 5 minute video & super-8 version featuring Marion Scemama (unfinished).
1990: Fear of Disclosure: The Psycho-Social Implications of HIV Revelation, 4 parts, in collaboration with Phil Zwickler.
1991: Site-less sounds/ Tellus #25. Compilation CD with various artists including David Wojnarowicz and Ben Neill performing "Vanishing act".
1992: ITSOFOMO: In the Shadow of Forward Motion /New Tone Records, CD of audio performance by David Wojnarowicz and Ben Neill.
FILMS (APPEARED OR ACTED IN):
1985: Stray Dogs, segment of Manhattan Love Suicides by Richard Kern (co-starring with Bill Rice).
1986: You Killed Me First, by Richard Kern, featuring Karen Finley, Lung Leg and David Wojnarowicz.
1990: Silence = Death, by Rosa von Praunheim and Phil Zwickler.
PLAYS:
1983: Sounds in the Distance/ Adapted and directed by Allen Frame and Kirsten Bates, Bill Rice's Garden, NYC, Berlin and BACA Downtown, Brooklyn.
PERFORMANCES:
1989: Itsofomo: In the Shadow of Forward Motion, co-conceived with musician Ben Neill. Multimedia performance presented in raw version for four nights at the Kitchen, NYC. Choreography Gloria McLean, videos edited by David Wojnarowicz and Phil Zwickler. Itsofomo was subsequently performed at Walker Art Center, Minneapolis; the Center of Contemporary Art, Seattle, San Francisco Art Institute; Hallwalls, Buffalo; and Exit Art, NYC.
Scope and Content Note
The David Wojnarowicz Papers are comprised of journals, correspondence, manuscripts, ephemera, photography, artwork, film, video and audio works.
The film, video and audio series (Series VIII, IX and X) of the David Wojnarowicz Papers contain audio, film and video works by David Wojnarowicz, as well as an extensive collection of film, video and audio source materials produced by Wojnarowicz. The collection of source and production materials reflects his interest in documenting environments through visual and audio recording media, as well as his tendency to reuse imagery from various media. The source materials include recorded journal entries, ambient recordings and interviews with friends and colleagues. Works by other downtown NYC artists and collaborators, such as Ben Neill, Richard Kern, Charles Atlas, Phil Zwickler, and Rosa von Praunheim are included in the collection as well as commercial works representing David Wojnarowicz's personal videotape library. Also included in the collection are taped radio interviews which document the NEA and Donald Wildmon/ American Family Association controversies. The collection also includes phone message tapes from David Wojnarowicz's personal answering machine. These tapes document significant events in his life such as the death of Peter Hujar. Descriptive information for items in these series is taken from any descriptive information provided by the artist on the object or its packaging.
The photography series (Series IX) contains multiple formats of photographs taken by David Wojnarowicz, mainly during the 1980s and early 1990s. Negatives, contact sheets, prints, and slides offer different media in which to examine Wojnarowicz's camera style, subject matter, and photographic collages. Contact sheets often have Wojnarowicz's notation on them as to which frames to reprint or enlarge, allowing a glimpse into his artistic choices. In addition, the envelopes which originally housed the contact sheets and negatives are full of Wojnarowicz's descriptions of the images inside, and sometimes his thoughts about their artistic merit. Negatives of important Wojnarowicz photographic work, such as the Rimbaud series, diorama shots, and photographs of Peter Hujar's death, are included. These negatives are not open to researchers. Wojnarowicz's many trips to Paris, Berlin and Mexico are well documented; inspirations gained on these trips can be traced throughout Wojnarowicz's work. The prints, which range in size from 3 x 5 in. to 16 x 20 in., often show a variety of exposures and darkroom techniques on the same image, detailing the options from which the final choice was made. Wojnarowicz's collection of commercial pornographic images is included here, and contains images which were later incorporated into several of the Sex series works. Many prints of the Rimbaud series, as well as many copies of a source photograph of a meteor crater, are contained in this series. A numbered run of slides contains most of Wojnarowicz's completed art works and documents, along with the prints and contact sheets, of many of his installation pieces.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged both alphabetically by subject/author heading and chronologically depending on the nature of the materials.
The files are grouped into 13 subject based series and further subdivided into subseries.
Series
Series I: Journals
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: Manuscripts
Series IV: Phone Logs
Series V: Art Magazines and Catalogue Contributions
Series VI: Biographical
Series VII: Subjects
Series VIII: Audio [SEE ALSO Accretions 2001]
Series IX: Photography
Series X: Video and Film
Series XI: Art Works
Series XII: Library
Series XIII: Objects and Artifacts
OVERSIZE - Series I: Journals and Diaries
OVERSIZE - Series V: Art Magazines and Catalogue Contributions
OVERSIZE - Series VI: Biographical
OVERSIZE - Series VII:Subjects
OVERSIZE - Series IX: Photography
OVERSIZE - Series X: Video and Film
OVERSIZE - Series XI: Art Works
OVERSIZE - Series XII: Library
Mapcase - Series VII: Subjects
Mapcase - Series XI: Art Works
Accretions 2001 - Media
Accretions 2001 - Series VI: Biographical
Related Material at the Fales Library and Special Collections
John Hall Papers
The Janine Vega Collection of David Wojnarowicz Letters
Separated Materials
Series XII: Library lists the books and other printed items that were in Wojnarowicz's library when it arrived at Fales and were removed from the archive. Most titles have been cataloged and can be retrieved by searching Bobcat, the Bobst library's online catalog.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room.
Appraisal
Due to extreme deterioration, Stuffed alligator with rope around its front right leg (item 092.2.0540) was deaccessioned in Fall of 2008.
In May 2018, Coffin with human remains (item 092.2.0539) was deaccessioned and returned to PPOW Gallery.
Photographers -- United States.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photography, Abstract; T-shirts; Amateur films -- Production and direction; Avant-garde films.; Character toys.; Correspondence.; Beads and sets of beads.; Artists and community -- United States; Celestial globes.; Photographs.; Negatives (photographic); AIDS (Disease) -- Social aspects -- New York (N.Y.); Downtown writers.; Figurines.; Poetry.; Handguns (small arms); Kachina dolls.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Logs (records); Masks (costume); Avant-garde poetry.; Avant-garde literature.; Experimental theater; Photography, Artistic; Photography |v Exhibitions.; Photographers |z United States |x Biography.; Photography |z United States.; Crosses (motifs); Reviews (document genre); Videocassettes.; Diaries; New York (N.Y.).; Audiotapes.; New York (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Scripts (documents); Religious objects.; Coins (money).; Super 8; Notes.; 16mm; Clippings (information artifacts); Praunheim, Rosa von, 1942-; Atlas, Charles; Wojnarowicz, David; Cooper, Dennis, 1953-; Hujar, Peter, 1934-1987; Indiana, Gary; Kern, Richard, 1954-
- Series I: Journals, 1971-1991
  Conditions Governing Access
  David Wojnarowicz's journals have been digitized and can be viewed in their entirety via links below each journal title.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of 2 boxes of journal notebooks with handwritten entries, encompassing the period from 1971 to 1990 (with discontinuities). The journals refer to sojourns in France, Berlin, Spain, Mexico, Louisiana, Illinois, Texas, and New York and include notes on art and film projects.
  - 1971: Aug.- Sept., cuid26077 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1976, cuid26078 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1977: July, NY Journal I, Brooklyn Heights, "Human Head I", cuid26079 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1977: Sept 5, "Human Head II", cuid26080 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1978: NY/France, cuid26081 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1978: Apr 22, NY, "Human Head III", cuid26082 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1978: Sept, Paris/Oct, Normandy, cuid26083 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1978: Normandy/Paris, cuid26084 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1979: Paris/Normandy, Nov 25-Mar 17, cuid26085 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1979: France, Mar 18 - Jun 1 (NY/ocean), cuid26086 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1979: NYC, Jun 6 - Aug 28, cuid26087 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1979-80: NY, 1979-1980; cuid26088 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1980: NY, Feb 2 - Apr 3, cuid26089 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1980, cuid26090 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1980-81: Aug, Paris/NY, 1980-1981; cuid26091 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1983: Feb 10 - 11, cuid26092 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1984: Berlin, journal fragment, cuid26093 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1986-87: Europe/America, 1986-1987; cuid26094 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Kingston, 1978; cuid26095 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    General
    Journal was wrongly dated 1987 when collection was processed. Finding aid was amended in 2012.
  - 1988: Spain/Paris/USA, cuid26096 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1989: dramas, drawings, notes, cuid26097 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1989-90: Louisiana/NYC/Berlin/Paris/Mexico, 1989-1990; cuid26098 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Empty ring-binder labelled "Journal NY-CA 1976," w/ photos on cover, cuid26099 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1976: Mss, cuid26100 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1976: photos, cuid26101 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1976: ephemera - tickets, receipts, cuid26102 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1987, cuid26103 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1990: Illinois, Sept., cuid26104 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1990: Illinois, Aug 17 1991, 1990-1991; cuid26105 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1991: "1991 or thereabouts", cuid26106 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1991: "Rough Notes 1991 NYC", cuid26107 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 19--?: blank, one drawing: "in the garden", undated; cuid26108 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 19--?: Mexico/Texas, undated; cuid26109 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 19--?: "When the plane lifted off", undated; cuid26110 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 19--?: back cover: "Paul's Monologue", undated; cuid26111 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 19--?: man falling onto train tracks on cover; first page: "la calle tiene fuego", undated; cuid26112 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 19--?: [no date], undated; cuid26113 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 19--?: [no date]: "Film with Steve Brown, Caven Point", undated; cuid26114 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1970-1992
  Scope and Contents note
  Series II comprises correspondence of both a personal and business nature and covers the 1970s through 1992. The bulk of the correspondence is directed to Wojnarowicz, although correspondence authored by Wojnarowicz is included. Correspondence is ordered chronologically (where possible) and then alphabetically by correspondent. Only recurring and noteworthy names are listed in the finding aid.
  - 1970s-various includes correspondence from David, cuid26115 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - pre-1989-misc. Undated, cuid26116 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1979-France: Jean Pierre Delage, cuid26117 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1979-Jean Pierre Delage Birthday card, cuid26118 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1980-Jean Pierre Delage/David Wojnarowicz, cuid26119 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1981-Jean Pierre Delage, cuid26120 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1982, cuid26121 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1983-Kathy Acker/Peter Hujar, cuid26122 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1984-Jean Pierre Delage/Peter Hujar/Gary Indiana, cuid26123 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1985, cuid26124 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1985-unidentified, cuid26125 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1986-Rauffenbart/D. Wojnarowicz, cuid26126 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1987-Art Against AIDS/Jody Falco/Lydia Lunch/Rauffenbart/Paul Smith/Catherine Texier/D. Voyna/D. Wojnarowicz, cuid26127 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1987-unidentified, cuid26128 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1988--Dennis Cooper/Jean Pierre Delage/Luis Frangella/Richard Kern/Stephen Koch/City Lights/High Risk/Between C&D/D. Voyna, cuid26129 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1988-unidentified, Judy, cuid26130 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1989-A-E, cuid26131 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1989-F-P: Robert Giard/Nan Goldin/Gary Indiana/Fran Leibowitz/Stephen Koch, cuid26132 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1989-Q-Z: Random House/Paul Smith/ D. Voyna/D. Wojnarowicz/Phil Zwickler, cuid26133 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1989-unidentified, cuid26134 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1990-A-C: Artists Space/Ronnie Burk/City Lights, cuid26135 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1990-D-H: GMHC/Nan Goldin, cuid26136 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1990-I-N: Stephen Koch/Fran Leibowitz/Patrick McDonnell/Jeff McMahon/New York Foundation for the Arts, cuid26137 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1990-P-R: PPOW/Random House/High Risk/Sur Rodney, cuid26138 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1990-S-Z: D. Wojnarowicz/D. Voyna/Emily XYZ, cuid26139 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1990-unidentified, cuid26140 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1990-re: housing/construction problem, cuid26141 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1991-A-E: Steve Abbot/Art Matters/Artspace/Dodie Bellamy/William S. Burroughs/Ronnie Burk/Dennis Cooper/L. Dahlberg/The Drawing Center/Jean Pierre Delage/Mark Ewert, cuid26142 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1991-F-M: Robert Giard/Nan Goldin/Wendy Jacob/Robert Gluck/Sylvere Lotringer/Steve McLean/Patrick McDonnell, cuid26143 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 1991-Mu-R: MOMA/New Museum/NY Foundation for the Arts/PPOW/Rhode Island School of Design/Turtle Bay Books, cuid26144 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 1991-S-Z: Amy Scholder/Sur Rodney/Catherine Texier/Joel Rose/Ira Silverberg/Jimmy Sommerville/Vintage Books/D. Wojnarowicz/Whitney Museum, cuid26145 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1991-unidentified, cuid26146 (Box 3, Folder 32)